{"tossups": [{"question": "In this state, the leader of the \u201cGlass Tax\u201d protest was pardoned by the president, because he was\u201cignorant of our language.\u201d In another incident in this state, David Bradford organized dissidents after the so-called \u201cBattle of Bower Hill.\u201d Fries\u2019s Rebellion took place in this state, as did an earlier action protesting a controversial 1791 tax favored by Alexander Hamilton. George Washington personally led militia into, for ten points, what state to put down the Whiskey Rebellion?", "answer": "Commonwealth of<b> Pennsylvania</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This party fractured over the issue of foreign debt, leading to a break from the Democratic Current. This party was formed in the Maximato period by Plutarco El\u00b4\u0131as Calles as the National Revolutionary Party. The \u201cHashtag YoSoy132\u201d student movement protested against this party after it won a 2012 election against the PRD. This party held its nation\u2019s presidency every year from 1928 to 2000, but only under Enrique Pe\u02dcna Nieto since then. For ten points, name this Mexican political party.", "answer": "<b>Institutional</b> <b>Revolutionary</b> Party (accept <b>PRI</b>, accept Partido <b>Revolucionario</b> <b>Institucional</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A schoolteacher who helped form this group was assassinated in 1949 after Prime Minister Nokrashy Pasha was slain. A member of this group, Sayyid Qutb [KUT-buh], wrote a 30-volume commentary on Islam that indirectly influenced Osama Bin Laden. Founded in Ismailia by Hassan al-Banna, this group\u2019s slogan is \u201cIslam is the Solution.\u201d President Nasser banned, for ten points, what Sunni Islamic movement in Egypt that rose to power during the 2012 Arab Spring under Mohamed Morsi?", "answer": "<b> Muslim Brotherhood</b> (accept<b> Society of the Muslim Brothers</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A Valois prince was elected king of this state but returned to France with much of its treasury. This country\u2019s history was marred by a series of invasions and conflicts known as \u201cThe Deluge.\u201d This country was created by the Union of Lublin and governed by a bicameral parliament known as the Sejm [SEYM]. This country\u2019s May 3 Constitution was the second codified constitution in the world. For ten points, name this country which was dismantled into three partitions by Russia, Prussia, and Austria.", "answer": "<b> Polish-Lithuanian</b> Commonwealth (accept<b> Rzeczpospolita</b>, accept<b> Poland-Lithuania</b>, accept Crown of the Kingdom of<b> Poland</b> and the Grand Duchy of<b> Lithuania</b>, accept<b> Commonwealth of Poland</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "John Price Buchanan, a governor of this state, faced a Knights of Labor-led uprising relating to the company use of convict labor in the Coal Creek War. A company named for this state that worked in coal, iron, and railroads later merged with U.S. Steel. Part of the Manhattan Project was located at this state\u2019s Oak Ridge National Laboratory near Knoxville. During the New Deal, FDR proposed a federal corporation to provide electricity named for, for ten points, what Southern state?", "answer": "<b> Tennessee</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "John Quincy Adams noted that this agreement was what \u201cspeculative philosophers have imagined as the only legitimate source of government.\u201d William Brewster is thought to have drafted this agreement. John Carver became governor after he was the first to sign this document, which created a \u201ccivil Body Politick.\u201d William Bradford was among the signers of, for ten points, what governing document of Plymouth Colony, named for the ship on which the Puritans sailed to America?", "answer": "<b> Mayflower Compact</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A surveillance software company with this name had its contract with the state of Utah suspended in April, 2020 after ownership\u2019s connections with the KKK were discovered. This instrument was played by Pete Seeger and Earl Scruggs at the Grand Ole Opry. For ten points, name this instrument associated with both traditional African-American music and bluegrass, typically circular with four or five strings.", "answer": "<b> Banjo</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This event was influenced by CIA propaganda that attempted to empower Cardinal Jozsef Mindszenty [mind-SENT-ee]. A government in this event issued the \u201cFor Freedom and Truth\u201d proclamation. Tensions from this event spilled over to the \u201cBlood in the Water\u201d water polo match at the Melbourne Olympics in the same year. J\u00b4anos [YAHN-oash] K\u00b4ad\u00b4ar was installed as chairman as a result of Soviet intervention in this event. For ten points, name this revolution in which Imre Nagy [NAHZH] tried to withdraw his country from the Warsaw Pact.", "answer": "<b> Hungarian</b> Revolution of 1956 (accept<b> Hungarian</b> Uprising) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One opponent of this event, Thomas Grantham, secured a garrison on the York River. The instigator of this event may have been jealous due to his inability to enter the Green Spring Circle. John Ingram replaced this event\u2019s leader after he died of dysentery. This event\u2019s participants were angry over a governor\u2019s refusal to adopt a harsh stance against the natives. For ten points, name this 1676 rebellion against Governor William Berkeley during which Jamestown was burned.", "answer": "<b> Bacon\u2019s</b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A ruler of this name was supposedly raised by a Sassanian king and appointed Nestorius as Archbishop of Constantinople. Another ruler of this name defeated the usurper Magnus Maximus at the Battle of the Save [SAH-vuh] and appointed Arbogast as<em> magister militum</em>. One man with this name was made co-emperor of the East following Valens\u2019s death at Adrianople. For ten points, give this name shared by two Roman emperors in the 4<em>th</em>and 5<em>th</em>centuries.", "answer": "<b> Theodosius</b> (accept<b> Theodosius</b> I or<b> Theodosius</b> II)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Beppu hid this leader\u2019s head after he took a mortal wound to the femur. This leader accepted Katsu Kaishu\u2019s surrender. This founder of the<em> Shigakko</em> military academies resigned in protest after his country decided in the Seikanron debate not to send him to Korea. One of this leader\u2019s campaigns was halted when he failed to take Kumamoto Castle, and he died at the Battle of Shiroyama. For ten points, name this leader who led the Satsuma Rebellion, known as \u201cthe last true samurai.\u201d", "answer": "Saigo<b> Takamori</b> (accept Saigo<b> Kokichi</b>, accept Saigo<b> Nanshu</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Since 1957, the Nizari holder of this title has been Aga Khan IV. American activist and philosopher Amina Wadud has received death threats for her assertion that women can hold this title. The Sevener and Twelver doctrines refer to the number of people believed to have held this title. According to Shia doctrine, the 12<em>th</em>holder of this title is subject to \u201cThe Occultation\u201d and will return as the Mahdi. For ten points, name this title, which in Sunni Islam refers to the prayer leaders in mosques.", "answer": "<b> Imam</b>", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "One leader of this country discredited China\u2019s \u201cthree worlds\u201d interpretation of communism in his book <em>Imperialism and the Revolution</em>. A man born with the name Ahmet Muhtar Zogolli faced an invasion led by Benito Mussolini in 1939 while serving as this country\u2019s king. Home to the port city of Durr\u00a8es, during World War Two, this country was led by Prime Minister Enver Hoxha [HOADJ-uh]. For ten points, name this Balkan country on the eastern shore of the Adriatic Sea.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Albania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man founded the American Ethnological Society along with John Russell Bartlett. William Crawford wanted this man as his running mate in the 1824 election, though this man dropped out. This man was the main negotiator of the Treaty of Ghent, ending the</b> <b>War of 1812. Agitators in the (+)</b> <b>Whiskey Rebellion were calmed down by this man,</b> <b>who continued his earlier work by serving as the head of New York City\u2019s branch of the (*)</b> National Bank. For ten points, name this man who served as Secretary of the Treasury for Thomas Jefferson and James Madison, dubbed the \u201cSwiss Founding Father.\u201d", "answer": "Albert<b> Gallatin</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The central location of this event was enclosed by the Blue Police. This event inspired\u201cZog nit keyn mol,\u201d sometimes called \u201cPartisan Song,\u201d by Hirsh Glick, a Vilna inmate. In 1970, after placing a wreath at a monument dedicated to the heroes of this event, (+) Willy Brandt suddenly knelt in front of the monument. The details of this event were collected in the Stroop Report, named for the man who oversaw the (*)</b> transportation of its victims to Treblinka and other camps. For ten points, name this largest Jewish revolt during World War Two, which occurred in a Polish city.", "answer": "<b> Warsaw Ghetto Uprising</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Singer Dorce Gamalama was criticized for attending the funerals of the perpetrators of this event and for saying she was \u201ccertain [they] had gone to heaven.\u201d One perpetrator of this incident struck at a nightclub named Paddy\u2019s Irish Bar twenty seconds before another</b> <b>attack at the Sari Club. The Sanglah (+)</b> <b>Hospital overflowed with victims of this event</b> <b>that killed 202 people. This event was perpetrated by Abu Bakar Bashir\u2019s group, Jemaah Islamiyah, and included an attack on the US Consulate in (*)</b> Denpasar. For ten points, name this series of terrorist attacks in Indonesia.", "answer": "2002<b> Bali bomb</b>ings (accept synonyms of \u201cbombings\u201d, such as attacks, killings, etc.) Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This man depicted three babies pulling on a kite string attached to a key in his painting </b><em><b>Benjamin Franklin Drawing Electricity from the Sky</b></em><b>. Another of this artist\u2019s works is set in the village of Shackamaxon and features the Lenape tribe resting under an elm tree.</b> <b>Another painting by this man depicts military officers (+)</b> <b>crowding around their fallen</b> <b>commander after his wounding in the Battle of the (*)</b> Plains of Abraham. For ten points, name this American painter of<em> Penn\u2019s Treaty with the Indians</em> and<em> The Death of General Wolfe</em>.", "answer": "Benjamin<b> West</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This group was weakened when the Engelbrekt rebellion broke out over a diminishing iron trade. Sten Sture the Younger\u2019s opposition to this group was stamped out after Archbishop Gustavus Trolle ordered a massacre of this group\u2019s enemies. This union was finally dissolved when (+) Christian II was defeated by Gustav I, marking the beginning of Vasa independence. This union had originally been founded by Margaret I to counteract the influence of the (*)</b> Hanseatic League. For ten points, identify this medieval union between Denmark, Sweden, and Norway.", "answer": "<b> Kalmar</b> Union", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This oil millionaire was central to the establishment of the Mid-Continent Oil and Gas Association. This man was endorsed by Jesse Owens and was the subject of the quote \u201cas Maine goes, so goes Vermont.\u201d Styles Bridges was tapped to be this man\u2019s running mate</b> <b>but was dropped as his name made the ticket sound like a famous (+)</b> <b>nursery rhyme.</b> <b>George Gallup infamously miscalculated poll results to reflect this man and Frank Knox winning the (*) </b> 1936 presidential election. For ten points, name this man who was defeated in that election by Franklin Delano Roosevelt while serving as governor of Kansas.", "answer": "Alf(red)<b> Landon</b> Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One holder of this position claimed that those who were saving money and living within their means and those who spent extravagantly both had the funds necessary to pay a \u201cbenevolence\u201d tax. That situation named for a holder of this position is Morton\u2019s fork. One holder of this position fled to the court of Louis VII after he refused to sign the (+) Constitutions of Clarendon. Four knights set out to \u201crid\u201d one</b> <b>king of a holder of this position in 1170, an event chronicled in the (*)</b> play<em> Murder</em> <em>in the Cathedral</em>. Thomas `a Becket was a holder of, for ten points, what position that heads the Church of England?", "answer": "<b> Archbishop of Canterbury </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}